William Merrow

1118 Girard Street NW, Washington, DC 20009 – william.merrow@gmail.com – 603-568-0366 Portfolio: https://wmerrow.github.io/

Summary

Information designer with proven experience creating web-based data visualizations for think tank and nonprofit clients on a range of public policy issues. Ability to approach projects from technical, creative, and project management standpoints. High attention to detail. Passion for clear and effective charts.

Skills

data visualization UX/UI design data analysis project management communication

Tools

Sketch Adobe Illustrator InVision R (ggplot2) Excel (VBA) Tableau HTML CSS

Education

Tufts University, B.A. 2011, *summa cum laude*, Phi Beta Kappa

Major: International Relations, Minor: Sociology; coursework in statistics and econometrics

School for International Training, Cochabamba, Bolivia, January to May 2010

Independent coursework:

Intermediate D3 for Data Visualization, Knight Center

Data Visualization with D3, Knight Center

Sketch 3: Mobile and Web Designs, Udemy

Front-end Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity

Professional Experience

Data Analyst & Visualization Specialist

Graphicacy, Washington, DC September 2015 to present

- Lead design of web-based visualizations for major think tank and nonprofit clients, using Adobe Illustrator, Excel, Tableau, and R to create clear and compelling graphics, working with researchers to ensure visualization design clearly communicates results and accomplishes goals
- Design websites, using Sketch to create high quality wireframes and comps in a deadline-based environment
- Develop content on data visualization best practices, creating data visualization style guides, leading workshops, and representing Graphicacy at conferences and events
- Lead data analysis projects, using R and Excel to manipulate and analyze large public datasets
- Manage large projects (\$100k+), managing developers and client communications to ensure project success
- Contribute to business development and strategic planning, securing new clients and helping to grow business

Princeton in Latin America Fellow in Monitoring & Evaluation The DREAM Project, Cabarete, Dominican Republic August 2014 to August 2015

- Led redesign, migration, and adoption of Salesforce database, creating objects, workflows, reports, and dashboards, using Tableau to visualize student data
- Managed and analyzed student data to assess education programs, identifying trends and ensuring data quality
- Led basic to advanced Excel workshops for all staff; trained managers in use of Salesforce and Tableau
- Managed data and reporting for USAID grant, leading to perfect score on audit of data system

Special Assistant to the President & CEO

InterAction, Washington, DC August 2011 to August 2014

Language Skills:

Spanish - professional German - conversational

- Coordinated data and communications for \$1.5b food security pledge by 30 international NGOs; prepared data for use in remarks of President Obama and Secretary Clinton
- Authored remarks, blogs, and articles for CEO on range of international development topics; authored policy briefs, published in 2012 Reality of Aid report on the role of corporations in foreign aid; coordinated drafting, editing, and copyediting of 42 policy briefs for flagship publication
- Managed advocacy projects, analyzing legislative language and meeting with congressional staff; managed CEO-level taskforces on aid reform and corporations in international development
- Promoted to Senior Associate level (2012) and Coordinator level (2014); voted Best Team Player

Congressional Program Intern

Inter-American Dialogue, Washington, DC June to August 2011

Research Intern

Americans for Campaign Reform, Concord, NH *June to August 2010*